



export const Questions = [
    //Question 1 
    { question: "What is the capital of USA ? " ,
options: ["Washington" , "Newyork" , "London"] ,
answer: "Washington"} ,
//Question 2
{
    question: "Who is the national poet of Pakistan ?",
    options: ["Mirza Ghalib" , "Jaun Elia" , "Allama Iqbal"] ,
    answer: "Allama Iqbal"
},
//Question 3
{
    question: "What is the capital of Pakistan ? " ,
    options: ["Islamabad" , "Karachi" , "Lahore"] ,
    answer: "Islamabad"
}, 
//Question 4
{
    question: "Who is the current PM of Pakistan" ,
    options: ["Yousuf Raza Gillani" , "Imran Khan" , "Nawaz Sharif"],
    answer: "Imran Khan"
},
//Question 5
{
    question: "What is the national sports of Pakistan",
    options: ["Cricket" , "Football" , "Hockey"],
    answer: "Hockey"
},
//Question 6
{
    question: "Pakistan is located in which continent ? " ,
    options: ["South Asia" , "East Asia" , "West Asia" , "Central Asia"],
    answer: "South Asia"
},
// 7
{
    question: "Which of the following countries is not bordered with Pakistan ?" ,
    options: [" Afghanistan" , "Bangladesh" , "India"] ,
    answer: "Bangladesh"
},

//8
{
    question: "Which animal is the national animal of Pakistan?" ,
    options: ["Lion" , "goat" , "Markhor"] ,
    answer: "Markhor"
},
//9
{
    question: "When did Pakistan won the cricket worldcup ?" ,
    options: ["1992" , "2019" , "1999"],
    answer: "1992"
},
//10
{
    question: "Which language is considered the *Lingua-Franca* in Pakistan ? ",
    options: ["English" , "Pashtu" , "Urdu"],
    answer: "Urdu" 
},
//11
{
    question: "Who the CEO of Facebook ?" ,
    options:[ "Mark Zuckerberg" , "Bill Gates" , "Anil Kapoor" ] ,
    answer: "Mark Zuckerberg"
},
//12
{
    question: "Which city in Pakistan is the capital of Punjab ?",
    options: ["Lahore" , "Rawalpindi" , "Gujrat"],
    answer: "Lahore"
},
//13
{
    question: "Which of these persons is a famous singer ? ",
    options:["Waqar Zaka" , "Babar Azam" , "Ali Sethi"],
    answer: "Ali Sethi"
},
//14
{
    question: "Who is the current president of Pakistan ?",
    options: ["Dr. Arif Alvi" , "Asif Zardari" , "Shehbaz Sharif"],
    answer: "Dr. Arif Alvi"
},
//15
{
    question: "Who is the current captain of Pakistan team?",
    options: ["Sarfaraz" , "Mishbah ul Haq" , "Babar Azam"],
    answer: "Babar Azam"
},






]

